SPIKE GU

+86 180-1642-9590 spike.gu@hotmail.com Shanghai, China



About Me

Passionate, dedicated, quick learner, high productivity.

7 years software testing experience on large scale commercial software product along with **global** engineering team collaboration experience.

3 years software testing experience on web/mobile based app with **continuous integration** and delivery in **scrum/agile** development.

8 years public speaking experience, strong presentation skills.

Work Experience

7/2016-till now

Quality Control Technician @Uber

Weekly smoke test on Uber apps (rider, driver app on Android and iOS), ad-hoc testing for outside of China growth, regional technical support and bug triaging for Ops, including generating globe product test runbook for local support, reproduce bug with log and assign to correct engineer, training Ops on daily issue handling and process.

1/2014-2/2016

Software QA Engineer (Mobile)@Autodesk

- Manual Testing on BIM 360 online project for heavy civil construction software, include back-end development using Ruby On Rails and front-end development on both **Web** and IOS.
- Mobile products testing based on a brand new cloud based mobile product for the next generation of field solution for infrastructure asset management.
- Defect tracking, customer follow up, project status monitoring.
- Pick-up devops related work for continuously integration using Jenkins, AWS, Capistrano, deploy build on CentOS.

1/2009-12/2013

In-house Trainer (part-time)

Work as an independent internal trainer to develop and delivery training courses for engineers to improve their technical presentation skills and public speaking skills. Help to build the internal instructors team.

5/2006-12/2013

Software QA Engineer @Autodesk

Worked on GIS related products and projects including AutoCAD Map3D, MapGuide, Autodesk Topobase, Autodesk Map Server etc. It's mainly focused on installation, license and web server

database related issue tracking.

- Test plan / test cases design according to system environment and features
- Execute smoke, regression, functional, performance and other test types
- Take active and responsible for bug report, track and fix to ensure product quality
- Support Beta forum for potential issues provided by customer and bug fix

Project Experience

7/2015-2/2016 Autodesk BIM 360 Heavy Construction

Responsibility: Manual Testing on BIM 360 online project for heavy civil construction software

- Conduct manual testing for app based on both web and mobile
- Web testing again various browser using dev tools (Chrome, Firefox, Safari and IE)
- Run continuous integration based on Jenkins, Capistrano and AWS
- Engage in agile development cycle (2 weeks per iteration)
- Track product quality using Jira and rally system

1/2014-7/2015 Autodesk Infrastructure Mobile

Project Description: Mobile products based on map system, providing a solution for infrastructure online management system- brand new cloud based mobile product for the next generation of field solution for infrastructure asset management.

Responsibility: QA Engineer, engage in daily stand-up meeting in scrum model, test plan drafting, test case writing and executing, mobile testing, exploratory testing.

4/2011-8/2011 Autodesk® Plant3D 2014

Project Description: Autodesk Plant 3D 2014 is a pipe design software which offers the solution for pipe design engineers. My job in the project is to test the ISO generation features including dimension, block and so on.

Responsibility: QA Engineer, case writing, testing and bug tracking

4/2011-8/2011 Autodesk® Map3D 2013

Project Description: Autodesk Map® 3D software connects CAD and GIS by providing the most powerful creation and editing tools for GIS professionals as well as the geospatial features that mapping and CAD technicians and civil engineers require.

Responsibility: QA Engineer, work across three feature teams, meet closely with U.S. colleagues, roll out project testing schedule, send weekly report based on project status, monitor the overall quality of the product.

3/2010-3/2011 Autodesk® Infrastructure Map Server 2012

Project Description: Autodesk® Infrastructure Map Server is a powerful development platform that enables developers to create spatial applications for the web and intranets quickly and easily. With it, you can integrate computer-aided design (CAD) and geographic information system (GIS) data, create applications and publish to a wide audience.

Responsibility: QA Engineer, test GIS related function: Position Finer, Dimension, Redlining, Street View, Export to KML, deal with customer issues from Customer Beta Program and product support, conduct performance testing to enhance the overall usability of the product.

5/2006-2/2010 Autodesk® Topobase 2008-2011

Project Description: Autodesk Topobase is an infrastructure asset management solution that provides centralized, flexible, and secure access to spatial information for planning, design, operations and business teams.

Responsibility: QA Lead, work closely with Switzerland team, draft project team schedule, test product, assist product support to solve customer issue, conduct series Topobase trainings to the whole division, use different tools to test the product: SQL, Oracle, Clarify, VSS, internal performance tool.

Training Delivered

1/2007 Oracle Spatial Sharing

7/2008 Microsoft Software Framework Sharing

6/2009 Autodesk® Topobase Inside

7/2009 Technical Presentation Training

9/2009 Web Knowledge Sharing

7/2010 Presentation Workshop Series

Affiliations

Certified Professional Managers Trainer (issued 2015.8 by The International Professional Managers Association)

Toastmasters, Shanghai People Square Toastmasters, President since 2006, advanced communicator

Recognition

Autobucks Winner 2011 Autobucks Winner 2011 Autodesk Best Presenter 2010 Autodesk Top Performer 2009

Education

Shanghai Tongji University

Software Engineering, Bachelor of Science, September 2002 - June 2006

Engineer College of Copenhagen in Denmark

Exchange student, Aug 2005 - Jan 2006

East China Normal University

Counseling Psychologist, May 2010 - Nov 2010

CIIC Training

International Professional Managers Training, 2014-2015

顾轶群



籍贯 上海 出生 84年3月 18016429590 (手机) spike.gu@hotmail.com

个人简介:

热情,高效,专注

- 7年大型商业项目全球化合作测试经验
- 3年互联网手机应用项目测试经验,系统持续集成发布经验
- 8年公众演讲和培训经验

工作经历:

2016/07-至今 优步中国 软件质量控制工程师

- 每周系统上线测试
- 对于优步中国之外的产品测试
- 区域技术支持和产品缺陷分配,包括运营经理培训和工程师缺陷沟通

2014/01-2016/2 欧特克软件 软件测试工程师

- 基于市政基础建设的在线系统 Web 端和 iOS 端测试,系统后端基于 Ruby on rails
- 应用 Jenkins, 亚马逊云和 Capstrano 等工具对系统采取持续集成和持续发布
- 基于 Cloud 的新一代场地施工解决方案的手机应用测试
- 参与 Scrum 模式下的产品质量测试与监测

2009/01-2013/12 欧特克软件 内部培训师 (兼职)

- 设计研发提高内部技术讲师团队演示技能的培训课程
- 讲授企业内部商务讲演培训课程

2006/01-2013/12 欧特克软件 软件测试工程师

- GIS 相关产品上的软件产品质量追踪,产品包括 AutoCAD Map3D, MapGuide, Autodesk Topobase, Autodesk Map Server
- 测试功能包括安装,授权(license),数据库和网络服务器相关功能

项目经历:

2015/07-2016/2 Autodesk BIM 360 Heavy Construction

- 基于市政基础建设的在线系统测试,系统后端基于 Ruby on rails, 前段基于 Web/iOS
- 应用 Jenkins, 亚马逊云和 Capstrano 等工具对系统采取持续集成和持续发布

2014/01-2015/7 Autodesk Infrastructure Mobile

基于地图系统的手机产品测试,为基础设施提供在线的解决方案。

2014/01-2014/6 Autodesk Plant 3D 2014

Autodesk Plant 3D 2014 是一个为化工厂提供管道设计的软件

2013/01-2014/1 Autodesk® Map3D 2011

Map3D 是一个基于 CAD 平台将地理信息系统和 CAD 无缝衔接的设计工具,为市政建设工程师提供了一套设计,管理,维护的统一解决方案。

2010/01-2013/1 Autodesk® Map Server2011

Map Server 是一个让开发者为网络 GIS 创建空间应用的开发平台。用户可以通过其讲 GIS 和 CAD 数据通过网络的方式发布和共享。

2006/01-2013/12 Autodesk Topobase

基于城市基础设施的大型数据库解决方案,涵盖土地管理,水力,电力和污水处理模块。

- 和美国项目组合作执行安装和授权测试
- 创建测试用例和测试设计文档
- 录入系统缺陷, 保证软件质量
- 组织每周英语研讨会

教育:

2005.8-2006.1 丹麦哥本哈根工学院,交换生计划 2002.9-2006.6 同济大学软件学院软件工程专业,本科

培训:

 2014-2015
 中智国际职业管理培训课程

 2010
 华师大心理咨询师培训

2006.10--至今 Toastmaster 国际演讲协会 人民广场分部

英语沟通能力提升,获 08 年演讲比赛冠军; 09 年 7 月出任俱乐部**主席**,领导团队提升演讲质量、拓展会员、举办演讲大赛,实践领导力与组织协调能力。

认证:

2011 心理咨询师二级

2015 注册执业国际培训师岗位证书